tuya.com 2019-08-26

# Tuya Smart Developer Center

Tuya Privacy Policy

Effective data: 2019-08-18

Last updated: 2019-07-19

Scope

Tuya Inc., its affiliates and subsidiaries (“we”, “us”, “our”, “Tuya”) recognizes that your privacy is important and we take it seriously. This Privacy Policy describes how we collect, receive, use, store, share, transfer and process your information, as well as your rights in determining what we do with the information that we collect or hold about you when you access or use (a) our websites and online properties, including

and our career portal (collectively, the “Sites”), (b) our Cloud-based IoT Platform, including

[iot.tuya.com](https://iot.tuya.com/)and any dashboards or portals that we make available to our customers, users and others (collectively, the “IoT Platform”) and (c) the Tuya Smart Cloud. The Sites, the IoT Platform and any services we provide in connection with one or more of the foregoing are collectively referred to as the “Services.”

The Services may contain links to other websites or online services that are operated and maintained by third parties and that are not under the control of or maintained by us. This Privacy Policy does not apply to how third parties collect, use, disclose or retain information. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of these third-party websites or services.

This Privacy Policy also covers our processing of information collected on behalf of and under the direction of our Clients through OEM branded Mobile Applications and Tuya APIs. The processing of such information is limited to the purpose of providing the service for which our Clients has engaged us and Tuya has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Data it processes. If you are a customer of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly. Under limited circumstances, when you are a user of Tuya Smart Mobile Application or Smart Life Mobile Application, we may collect and process some of your Personal Data for our own business benefit, please refer to our

Tuya Mobile Privacy Policy

for details .

In this Privacy Policy, “Personal Data” means information that can be used to identify an individual, either from that information alone, or from that information and other information we have access to about that individual.

What Personal Data do We Collect

1\. Information You Voluntarily Provide Us. 

• Account or Profile Data: When you register an account with us, we may collect your name and contact details, such as your name, email address, mailing address, phone number, user name, and login credentials.

• Name and Role Details: When you visit our websites, fill out our online forms, or engage with our support team, we may collect your name and role related information, such us your name, email address, and work/company information.

• Job Application Information: When you apply to work for us, we may collect your education and professional experience related information, such as school attended, course of study, academic degree obtained, grades, employment history, professional certification/licenses received.

2\. Information We Collect Automatically.

When you use our Sites and Services, we may collect certain information, including Personal Data, about your use of the Sites and Services: 

• Device Information: When you interact with our Sites and Services through hardware, we automatically collect device information, such as the unique device ID number of your device (“UDID”), the MAC address of your devices, IP address, wireless connection information, operating system type and version, browser type and version, push notification identifier, and mobile network information. 

• Usage Data: During your interaction with our Sites and Services, we automatically collect usage data relating to visits, clicks, downloads, messages sent/received, and other usage of our Sites and Services.

• Location Information: We may collect information about your real-time precise or non-precise geo-location when you interact with our Sites and Services through your devices.

• Smart Device Data: “Smart Devices” refers to those nonstandard computing devices produced or manufactured by hardware manufacturers, with human-machine interface and the ability to transmit data that connect wirelessly to a network, including: smart home appliances, smart wearable devices, smart air cleaning devices, etc. When you use Smart Devices that are connected to our Services, depending on the capability of your Smart Devices, we may collect certain types of your data in order to provide your services you have requested or purchased, such as videos, images, health related data etc. Please refer to our

Tuya Mobile Privacy Policy

for details.

3\. Cookies and Similar Tracking Technologies

When you visit the Sites and Services, we and service providers on our behalf may send one or more “cookies,” which are small data files, to your Devices to uniquely identify your browser and let us help you log in faster and enhance your navigation through the Sites. Cookies help us measure, for example, the total number of visitors to our Sites, the number of visitors to each page of our Sites, how our users use and interact with the Services, and the domain names of our visitors” Internet service providers. You can reset your web browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. If you do not want cookies to be installed on your Device, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to decline the use of cookies. Please be aware that some features of the Sites and Services will not function properly if the ability of your Device to accept cookies is disabled.

We may also use web beacons to track usage patterns of users of the Services. Additionally, we may use HTML-based emails sent to our users to track which emails are opened by recipients. The information is used to enable more accurate reporting and make the Services better for you.

We honor do-not-track signals or similar technologies that our systems detect and identify. We do not track, plant cookies, or use advertising when such do-not-track (DNT) browser mechanism is in place on your Device.

Purpose and Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data

The purpose for which we may process information about you are as follows: 

• Provide You Services. We process your account and profile data, device information, usage data, location information, and Smart Device data in order to provide Services that you have requested or purchased. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use.

• Improve Our Services. We process your device information, usage data, location information and Smart Device data to analyze trends and to track your usage of our Sites and Services as necessary to develop and improve our websites, and provide our users with more relevant and useful content. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use. 

• Account Management: We process your Personal Data to create and manage accounts when you register with us. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use. 

• Handle Contact and Support Request: We process your Personal Data to contact you to offer help based on diagnostic information about your Smart Devices, to fulfill your requests, respond to your inquiries and to provide support. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use.

• Marketing Communication: We process your Personal Data to inform you about services that we believe may be of interest to you. If we do so, each communication we send you will contain instructions permitting you to opt-out of receiving future communications of that nature. The legal basis for this processing is your consent.

• Non-Marketing Communication: We process your Personal Data to send you important information regarding the Services, changes to our terms, conditions, and policies and/or other administrative information. Because this information may be important, you may not opt-out of receiving such communications. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use. 

• Research. We process your Personal Data for our internal business purposes, such as data analysis, audits, developing new products or services, enhancing and improving the Services and identifying usage trends. The legal basis for this processing is to perform our contract with you according to our Terms of Use.

• Legal Compliance: We may process your Personal Data as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) to comply with applicable laws and regulations; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations, business and systems; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of other users, including you; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

Who do We Share Personal Data with?

At Tuya, we only share Personal Data in ways that we tell you about. We do not sell your Personal Data to third parties and we limit disclosure of your Personal Data as listed below:

• To our third-party service providers who perform certain business-related functions for us, such as website hosting, data analysis, payment and credit card processing, infrastructure provision, IT services, customer support service, e-mail delivery services, and other similar services to enable them to provide services to us.

• To our customers and other business partners who provide you, directly or indirectly, with your Smart Devices, and/or networks and systems through which you access and use our Sites and Services.

• To an affiliate or other third party in the event of any reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business, assets or stock (including without limitation in connection with any bankruptcy or similar proceedings). In such an event, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership, incompatible new uses of your Personal Data, and choices you may have regarding your Personal Data.

• As we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) to comply with applicable laws and regulations; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities, including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions; (e) to protect our operations, business and systems; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of other users, including you; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

• To subsidiaries or affiliates within our corporate family, to carry out regular business activities.

• Except for the third parties described above, to third parties only with your consent. 

Transfer of Information Collected

To facilitate our operation, we may transfer, store and process your Personal Data in jurisdictions other than where you live. Laws in these countries may differ from the laws applicable to your country of residence. When we do so, we will ensure that an adequate level of protection is provided for the information by using the following approach:

If you would like further detail on the safeguards we have in place, you can contact us directly as described in this Privacy Policy.

Security

We use commercially reasonable physical, administrative, and technical safeguards to preserve the integrity and security of your Personal Data. Tuya provides various security strategies to effectively ensure data security of user and device. As for device access, Tuya proprietary algorithms are employed to ensure data isolation, access authentication, applying for authorization. As for data communication, communication using security algorithms and transmission encryption protocols and commercial level information encryption transmission based on dynamic keys are supported. As for data processing, strict data filtering and validation and complete data audit are applied. As for data storage, all confidential information of users will be safely encrypted for storage. If you have reason to believe that your interaction with us is no longer secure (for example, if you feel that the security of any account you might have with us has been compromised), you could immediately notify us of the problem by emailing

[privacy@tuya.com](mailto:privacy@tuya.com) in accordance with the section below.

Data Subject Rights

We respect your rights and control over your Personal Data. You may exercise any of the following rights by:

• Creating a ticket in the Support Center, or;

You do not have to pay a fee and we will aim to respond you within 30 days. In your request, please make clear what information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your Personal Data deleted from our database or otherwise let us know what limitations you would like to put on our use of your Personal Data. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request, for security purposes. 

You may:

• Request access to the Personal Data that we process about you;

• Request that we correct inaccurate or incomplete Personal Data about you;

• Request deletion of Personal Data about you;

• Request restrictions, temporarily or permanently, on our processing of some or all Personal Data about you;

• Request transfer of Personal Data to you or a third party where we process the data based on your consent or a contract with you, and where our processing is automated;

• Opt-out or object to our use of Personal Data about you where our use is based on your consent or our legitimate interests.

You may opt-out from receiving marketing-related emails or other communications from us on a going-forward basis by emailing [privacy@tuya.com](mailto:privacy@tuya.com). We will comply with your opt-out request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please also note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing-related messages from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, and you cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages. We partner with a third party to display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third-party partner may use cookies or similar technologies in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to opt out of interest-based advertising click

or if located in the European Union click

[here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Please note you will continue to receive generic ads.

Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits users of the Software that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personal Data to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please contact us in accordance with the “[privacy@tuya.com](mailto:privacy@tuya.com)” section below. We do not disclose Personal Data to third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent.

Data Retention 

We process your Personal Data for the minimum period necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy, unless there is a specific legal requirement for us to keep the data for a longer retention period. We determine the appropriate retention period based on the amount, nature, and sensitivity of your Personal Data, and after the retention period ends, we will destruct your Personal Data. When we are unable to do so for technical reasons, we will ensure that appropriate measures are put in place to prevent any further such use of your Personal Data. 

Children’s Privacy

Protecting the privacy of young children is especially important to us. The Services are not directed to individuals under the age of thirteen (13), and we request that these individuals do not provide any Personal Data to us. We do not knowingly collect Personal Data from anyone under the age of thirteen (13) unless we first obtain permission from that child’s parent or legal guardian. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from anyone under the age of thirteen (13) without permission from that child’s parent or legal guardian, we will take steps to remove that information.

Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (send to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

Contact Us

If you have any questions about our practices or this Privacy Policy, please contact us as follows:

Tuya Inc. 

Postal Mailing Address: 75 E Santa Clara St, 6th Floor, San Jose, CA 95113 or 5, 7, 8 and 11th Floor, No. 3 Building, More Centre, 87 Gudun Road, Xihu District, HangZhou, China.

For European Union data subject, you have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority concerning Tuya’s data processing activities. For questions, or to exercise your rights as an EU data subject, please contact our EU Representative here: 

Name: Data Protection Representative
